KUNAL BHANSALI

Shriraj Hill View, Bhusari Colony, Kothrud, Pune • 9657233686 / 7066666302 kunalbhansali09@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Network Engineer with 5+ years of experience in network design, Network Infrastructure, Network change, Network Security (Palo Alto, Cisco ASA) and Cloud (AWS, AZURE). Skilled in delivering technical support, managing network operations, and maintaining enterprise-wide area networks across multi-platform and high-uptime Data Center environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Genpact, Pune (Assistant Manager)

NOV 2022 - Present

- Oversaw the design, planning, and management of organization-wide local area network, wide area network, network segment, and internet system.
- Designed, configured, and change for end-to-end Setup for Work from office and Work from home including Firewall, Routing, Switching and Cloud changes.
- Delivered Different Services to Business according to requirement and Applied routing and Switching changes including BGP, OSPF, MPLS.
- Applied Firewall changes including NAT, QOS, Security policies, Firewall Rules, Configure new Palo alto Firewall.
- Experience in Planning, Executing project as per the Client requirement which includes the Setup for AZURE VDI, AWS Workspace, AWS Connect, Internet through Proxy, Internet through Local Breakout.
- Hands-on Experience in Routing & Switching, Palo alto and Cisco ASA Firewall, ZScaler, AWS.
- Hands-on Experience on Tools like Service-Now, Logic Monitor, Solar wind, Tufin, Helpmate, Putty, Secure CRT.
- Implement effective security measures to protect data, software, and hardware

Vodafone Idea Ltd (Manager IPINM Network And Infrasturcture)

FEB 2022 - OCT 2022

- Working on Vodafone Idea CORE/CEN/Mobility/Cloud network related configuration & troubleshooting.
- Responsible to solve network related issue of FLDS/CEN/IPCPE/CORE/CLOUD and thus has to cordinate with the relevent team to resolve issue within SLA.
- Serve as a incident manager for the service restoration process during major and minor outage P1/P2/P3 of Mobility Services 2G/3G/4G and Outages of Vodafone core network such as Node unreachable, WAN link restoration and provide field support if need to solve issue.
- Working as a project manager for business and SNOC team for implementation of new process and tool thus coordinate with vendor for tool optimization releasing new requirement.
- Working on devices like Cisco, Juniper, Nokia, Huawei, ZTE, Ericsson.
- Establishing a strong relation with client to get the things done, providing feedback and suggestion to improve network, performance and efficiency.
- Hands-on experience of Internet links/MPLS/ITMPLS/P2P links and Tools involved for monitoring alarm/dashboard and report generation.

- Working on ISP/Routing/Switching/MPLS/Traffic Engineering related configuration & troubleshooting.
- Responsible to solve issues related to Link Down/latency/packet drops/browsing for Internet
 and thus has to coordinate with International Upstream Global Peering ISP's like C&W,
 Vodafone NSU and domestic peers like TCL, Bharti, Reliance in order to solve the Issue.
- Provide the remote support to field activities for services restoration which are configured on IPRAN, ISP, NLD and UBR media. Understanding of change, incident and problem management.
- Responsible for IP routing using BGP, OSPF, Static Routers and switching using STP/VTP/VLAN.
- Coordinate with different teams like transmission, CEN & FLDS Teams to resolve network issue
- Working on devices like Cisco 7K, 9K, Juniper, Nokia, Huawei.
- Hands-on experience of Internet links/MPLS/ITMPLS/P2P links, UBR (Radwin, Cambium) media and Tools like Secure CRT, Putty, ECI, NGPTN, HPSM.

ACE Computer (Third Party Pay Role Company)

June 2019 - OCT 2019

- Responsible for IP routing using BGP, OSPF, Static Routers and switching using STP/VTP/VLAN.
- Coordinate with different teams like transmission, CEN & FLDS Teams to resolve network issue.
- Working on devices like Cisco 7K, 9K, Juniper, Nokia, Huawei.
- Hands-on experience of Internet links/MPLS/ITMPLS/P2P links, UBR (Radwin, Cambium) media and Tools like Secure CRT, Putty, ECI, NGPTN, HPSM.

EDUCATION

M.TECH In Computing System and Infracture

AUG 2020 - JUNE 2022

- BITS PILANI, Hyderabad Campus
- Specialization in Computing System and Infracture AUG 20

Bachelor in Electronic and Tele-Communication Engineering

JUNE 2015 - JUNE 2018

PVPIT Pune, Savitribai Phule PUNE University

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: MPLS, Routing, NAT, ACL, Object-Group, Firewall (PALO ALTO, CISCO ASA), VPNs, BGP, Firewall management, Cloud Technology (AWS, AZURE) etc.
- Languages: English, Hindi, Marathi
- Awards/Activities: Received the "Excellence Performance" Award for outstanding contributions to NAC project for BMO Business

• **Date of Birth**: 28/02/1996

DECLARATION: I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Pune

Date : Kunal Bhansali